（ナルト）出た！
There it is!
あれ？　ここ島じゃなかったっけ？
Huh? Wasn't this an island?
なんで　陸続きになってんだ？
How come it's connected to land?
（キラービー）細かいことは気にすんな。
行くぞ　すんなり！
Minor stuff you don't need to know…
Now, are ya ready?
'Cuz here we go.
Attack of the Gedo Statue
もう花札にも飽きたな。
I'm bored with playing cards.
別の余興はないのかえ？
How else can
we amuse ourselves?
しかたないのう。
We have no choice.
（ゼツ）見つけたぞ　ここだ。
Found them!
This is it!
大名を狩る前に　お前を
倒さねばならないようだな。
So before I can get
the Feudal Lords,
I have to get
through you first, huh.
（メイ）私たちをね。
Get through us.
クククク…。
少し　外が騒がしいのう。
It's noisy outside.
落ち着いて
考えられぬではないかえ。
How am I supposed
to concentrate?
♪～
《溶遁》
Lava Style!
（長十郎）はあ～っ！！
《長十郎…》
Chojuro…
I won't let you…!
やらせないぞ！　はあ～っ！！
ん？
《ゼツ：八尾と九尾のチャクラ…。
The Eight and
Nine Tails' chakra!
ついに出てきたな。
They've appeared at last!
知らせなくては》
I must send word.
八尾と九尾が
出てきたみたいだよ。
Looks like the Eight Tails and
Nine Tails have appeared.
八尾と九尾の２人
出てきたけど→
So the Eight Tails and
Nine Tails are out.
大名たちはどうすんの？
But what about the Feudal Lords?
やっぱ　交渉の駒として
捕獲しておいたほうがいいよね。
We should capture them to use
as bargaining chips, right?
（マダラ）いや　大名どもはもういらん。
No, we don't need
the Feudal Lords anymore.
やつらを捕らえれば　国側から→
If we capture them,
the nations would pressure
the Allied Shinobi Forces.
里の忍連合へ圧力がかかるが→
もともと
そうして八尾と九尾を→
But from the very beginning,
those lords were mere tools
出させるための
駒にすぎなかった。
to lure the Eight and
Nine Tails out.
（マダラ）八尾と九尾が
出てきた以上→
Now that the Eight and
Nine Tails have emerged,
そんなまわりくどい
やり方は必要ない。
there's no need for
indirect measures.
あの雷影のことだ→
We're dealing with the Raikage.
この戦争で大名どもが
交渉価値などないと→
He's aware that in this war,
the Feudal Lords have no value.
ハナからわかっている。
月の眼計画が成功すれば→
If Project Tsuki no Me succeeds,
it's all over.
すべてが終わりなんだからな。
な～んだ　せっかく黒ゼツが
水影とやりあってんのに。
What, really?
So Black Zetsu is fighting
Mizukage for nothing?
いや　だからといって
大名どもを無視できないのが→
No. Shinobi still cannot disregard
the Feudal Lords who hired them.
雇われ忍どもだ。
黒ゼツには
ゲリラ戦を続けさせろ。
Tell Black Zetsu to continue
his guerilla assault.
水影たちを
そこへ釘付けにしておけば→
By stalling the Mizukage
and her men there,
敵の戦力を分散させておける。
we'll be able split up
the enemy's battle strength.
あっ　そういうことね。
You're right.
で　トビは　どうすんの？
And what about you, Tobi?
やっと　俺も参戦だ。
It's finally time for me
to join the battle.
まずは　代用品を奪う。
First, I'm going to steal
the substitute.
（４人）忍法！
– Ninja Art!
（４人）四紫炎陣！
– Four Flames Formation!
（ダン）よくやったぞ。
Well done!
この結界の中では
穢土転生で操られようとも→
Once inside this barrier,
even those controlled by
the Reanimation Jutsu are helpless.
何もできない。
（チョウザ）あぁ　はい。
Yes…
Right.
（テンテン）やぁ～！
（黄ツチ）こいつで　ラストだ！
This is…
the last one!
死ぬ…　誰か…。
I'm dying. Help me…
チャクラの使いすぎだ。
You used too much chakra.
もう　この忍具は使うな！
Don't use this Ninja Tool anymore!
そんな…　すごく使えるのに。
But, I'm so good with it.
（ダルイ）ありがとよ！
木ノ葉のでかいの。
Thanks, big guy from the Leaf!
（角都）まだまだ。
It's far from over.
（角都）これからだ。
This is just…the beginning.
たいした状況判断だな。
That's some assessment.
ここは　俺たちの勝ちだ。
We're the victors here.
海岸線は死守したぜ。
We've defended
the coastline to the end.
お前たちの上陸作戦は　失敗だ。
Your amphibious operation
is a failure.
（マダラ）口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
お…　お前は！
まさか！
Y-You're…
No way!
♪～
何だ？　あれは！
（いの）チョウジより　でかい！
What is that?!
It's bigger than Choji.
（シカマル）嫌な予感がする。
I have a bad feeling about this.
ヘッ…　で…　でかいってだけじゃな。
I-It's not just big…
たいした　状況判断だな
お前こそ。
That's some assessment
on your part too.
来い！　チョウジ！
Come! Choji!
（チョウジ）角都と　ヒザシさんのほうを
お願いします　皆さん。
Please deal with
Kakuzu and Hizashi!
僕は　あれを！
I'll handle that one!
封印班！
Sealing Corps!
いけ　外道魔像。
Go, Gedo Statue!
♪～
あそこか。
It's there, eh…
チョウザ。
Choza…
Dad!
父さん！
あぁ！
Yeah!
今だ　チョウジ！
Now, Choji!
でやぁ～っ！！
うわぁ～！
《くっ…　止められた！？》
He stopped me?!
なんだと！？
What happened?
上は　どうなっている！？
What's happening up there?!
Now then…
さて…。
とんでもないチャクラだ！
Incredible chakra!
ダルイ第一部隊の戦場に
とてつもないチャクラ体が出現！
An immense chakra field has
appeared on the battlefield
near Darui's First company!
《なんだ　こいつは！？》
What is it?!
第一部隊と　つながりました。
We reached the First Company.
It appears to be some sort
of humanoid monster!
そいつは
人型の　でかいバケモノのようです！
And it seems to be controlled by…
で　そいつを操ってるのが…。
（エー）誰だ！？
Who is it?!
We believe it's Madara Uchiha.
うちはマダラだと思われます！
（シカク）だとすると　作戦を
立て直さなきゃ　なりませんね。
If that's true, we must revise
our battle strategy.
（綱手）頭が動いただと？
目的は　なんだ？
The leader joined the battle?
For what reason?
（シカク）判断材料が　まだ足りません。
We don't have enough data
for an assessment.
Naruto, preserve that mode
for the fight ahead.
（キラービー）ナルト　戦闘まで
そのモードは　とっておけ。　温存！
Use up your strength,
and you'll end up seeing red.
いざって時に　力尽きたら大損！
ちんたらしてらんねえよ！
I can't waste anymore time!
連絡！　キラービー　うずまきナルト２名！
Incoming message!
Killer Bee and Naruto have
both broken through the barrier,
結界を抜け　外へ出たもようです！
なんだと！？
and escaped.
What?!
人柱力ですら出られぬ
結界のはずだぞ。
That barrier is supposed to
be impenetrable, even to Jinchuriki!
人柱力　２人での連携による
結界破りは→
No one foresaw two Jinchuriki
coordinating an escape!
想定外の動きだったようです！
２人だと！？
Two of them?!
ビー様も　協力したようですね。
It seems Master Bee
is helping out.
え～い！
Damn!
さて　どうしたものか？
Now what are they up to?
人柱力は
わしが　直接　出て止める。
I will personally stop the Jinchuriki.
Tsunade, you come too!
綱手　お前も来い！
本部での判断は　どうする？
Who will manage Headquarters?
木ノ葉のシカク！
了解しました。
Shikaku of the Leaf!
Understood.
こっちは　任せてください。
You can leave this to me.
All right!
Follow me, Tsunade!
よし　ついてこい　綱手！
雷影様　壁を壊すのは
なしで　お願いします。
Lord Raikage!
Please don't break down
any walls.
行こう。
うむむ…　うむ！
Let's go.
Oh…right.
くっ…。
なんてこった…。
I can't believe this.
下がれ！　総員　海岸まで退避！
Get back!
Everyone, retreat to
the coastline!
《土遁　山土の術！》
Earth Style! Mountain Jutsu!
でぇ～い！
♪～
なんなのよ　あれ！？
What is that thing?
なんという強さ！　ケタ外れだ！
What power…
It's extraordinary!
連合会議の時
砂のテマリが　言っていたことや→
Taking into consideration
all the data gathered so far,
集めた情報から推測して
もしかして　あれが…。
and the data Temari of the Sand
gave to the Allied Forces Council,
I wonder if that's…
((砂の風影からの情報では→
According to the Kazekage's intel,
a Jinchuriki's powers are sealed
儀式用の　巨大な人型の像に
人柱力の力を封印するそうだ。
inside a giant humanoid statue
used for the ritual.
(ビーの　タコ足分身も
おそらく吸い込まれている))
Bee's octopus leg clone
most likely has been absorbed into it.
人型のバケモノ…。
A humanoid monster…
まさか　あれが　そうなのか！？
Don't tell that's it?!
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
わしのとっておきを
こうも　あっさりと…！
My reserved special move
had no effect at all.
《あれに人柱力の力を
封印するってことは…》
Sealing the Jinchuriki powers
into that thing…
《つまり…》
means…
この！
うお！
Why you—!
マズい！
Damn it!
その忍具は渡さねえよ。
You can't have that Ninja Tool!
忍具はいらん。
欲しいのは　この中のものだ。
I don't want the Ninja Tool!
I want what's inside.
I'll return the Ninja Tool later.
後で　忍具は返してやる。
そんなに欲しければな。
If you want it that badly.
（シカマル）
九尾のチャクラを持つ金角銀角を→
You took advantage of
the Gold and Silver Brothers,
who possess the Nine Tails' chakra,
by utilizing them on the frontlines.
最前線で利用するだけ利用して→
頃合いを見て今度は
金角銀角の九尾のチャクラを→
Now that you're through with them,
you want to seal their chakra
inside that monstrosity…
あのデカいのに封印する。
連合にも鋭いのが…。
多少は　いるなぁ。
Seems the Allied Forces have
a shrewd one in their midst.
違うか？
Am I wrong?
お前
敵にしておくには惜しい男だ。
What a shame
that you're my enemy.
ってことはあのデカいのが？
まさか…。
Don't tell me that giant is…
No way…
うお！
くそ！
Damn it!
シ…　シカマル！
Shikamaru?!
大丈夫か　シカマル。
Are you all right, Shikamaru?
助かったぜ　チョウジ。
You're a lifesaver, Choji!
（ダルイ）
二度も手を焼かせちまって…。
Sorry to bother you twice.
（黄ツチ）気にするな…。
Don't stress over it.
すみません…。
I apologize.
（ダルイ）ヤツは？
So what happened to him?
（黄ツチ）忍具ごと消えた。
He disappeared with
the Ninja Tool.
退いたのか…？
They retreated?
（角都）グッ…。
（ダン）チョウザ　封印だ！
早く　早く俺を封印しろ！
Choza, seal me!
Hurry…
Hurry and seal me!
♪～
Don't be afraid!
Surround him!
（ミフネ）怯むな！　囲め！
（黄ツチ）戦局は一気に不利になった。
The tide of the war has suddenly
changed in their favor.
本部との連絡を密にして
立て直すぞ　ダルイ。
Darui, we must contact
HQ secretly and regroup.
わかってるっす。
I know.
（黄ツチ）じき夜だ。
It's almost dark.
We have to be prepared for
a night invasion and keep our eyes open.
夜襲に備えての睨みあいになる。
Losing this war is not an option.
《この戦争　負けは許されない》
Make no doubt about it.
《念には念。
積年の念願　月の眼計画。
My long-standing desire…
Project Tsuki no Me…
ついに明日　それが成就する》
shall be realized tomorrow,
at long last…
（カブト）ヤツめ…　もう金角銀角を…。
He's already sealed
Kinkaku and Ginkaku?
He only has part of
the Eight Tail's chakra…
八尾のチャクラは
ひと握りしか封印してない。
足１本分…。
one part of his tentacles.
少し
慌てすぎな気もするけどね…。
I think you're rushing into this,
夜は　キミの策にのる。
but I'll go along with
your plans tonight…
僕の手駒は…
温存させてもらうよ。
while I keep some of
my pieces in reserve.
（サイ）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
（カカシ）よくやった　サイ。
休めるだけ　休んでおけ。
Good work, Sai.
Get as much rest as you can.
カカシさん…。
Kakashi…
よし！　見張りに立てる者は
俺のそばに集合！
All right!
Those who are fit for guard duty,
gather around!
（ネジ）敵の姿が見えない…。
I can't see the enemy.
（キバ）どうするよ？
引くのか？　攻めるのか？
What'll we do?
Retreat? Or advance?
今　この部隊には
誰も隊長がいない。
Right now, this company is
without captains.
この場の守りを固めて
命令があるまで待機しよう。
We'll just have to stand
our ground and wait for orders.
まっ　ここは感知タイプが
揃っているからな。
Luckily, we have a bunch
of Sensory-Type ninja…
守るには　うってつけか。
（赤丸）ワン！
who are ideal for this.
（オオノキ）来ぬな…。
They're not coming…
（我愛羅）砂に何も感じない。
I don't sense anything
in the sand either.
引いたとみて
間違いないだろう。
We can safely assume
they've retreated.
（オオノキ）ハァ…　穢土転生なら→
I should think the wiser move
with the Reanimation
不死身を強みに戦い続けるのが
上策じゃろうに。
is to keep raising the dead
and fight hard.
それを上回る策が
あるというのか…？
So are you saying they have
a better plan than that?
（マツリ）我愛羅様　どうぞ！
Lord Gaara, please use this!
（ユカタ）体力を蓄えておかなければ。
You must conserve your strength.
俺よりも　まずこちらに。
Give that to him first.
えぇ　この　ちっちゃい
おじいちゃんにですか？
Huh? To this puny old man?
わしゃ　土影ぜよ。
（２人）え～！？
I am the Tsuchikage.
– Huh?!
夜陰に紛れ
何を仕掛けてくるか　わからん。
We have no idea what they may
be planning in the dark of night.
よいな？
Stay on guard at all times.
警戒を怠るでないぞ。
（みんな）はっ！
– Yes, sire!
（テンテン）どこよ…　私の忍具！
Where is my Ninja Tool?!
返してよ～。
I want it back!
（いの）もう使うなって
言われたんでしょ！
You were told not
to use it anymore!
（テンテン）やだ～。
I don't want to!
すっごい使えんのに。
I'm really good with it!
もったいないわよ。
It's such a waste!
マダラに宝具を奪われたことは
本部へ伝えた。
I notified HQ that Madara
has taken a Treasured Tool.
尾獣のチャクラを奪っていったとな。
And that he got
the Tailed Beast's chakra.
ほんと　すみません。　失態です。
I'm very sorry.
This was my fault.
もっと早くに気づいていれば…。
If only we had
realized it sooner…
いや　お前たちはよく対応した。
No, you responded well.
阻止できなかったのは
しかたがない。
ともかくも
今日は　敵を撃退したんだ。
（いのいち）８万のうち
およそ４万…。
今日倒れた　忍連合の仲間の数だ。
１０万のうち　５万…。
今日倒した　暁側の数だ。
双方　半数ずつか…。
しかし　こちらは生身の人間…。
対する向こうは…。
《今…　行くってばよ。
みんな！》
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→